- [women giggling]
- [water rushing]
[whooping]
[Juno] Come on!
Whoo-hoo! Whoo!
[indistinct shouting]
- [Juno] Hold on. girls!
- [Beth] Here we go!
- [Sarah] Whoo-hoo!
- [Juno] More to the left!
Paddle!
- [Paul] Can you see her?
- Mommy!
[women scream]
[all screaming]
Look out!
[screaming continues]
[laughing. screaming]
[Juno] Yeah. all right! Whoo-hoo!
Yes!
[whooping]
Mommy!
- Hey. guys!
- Hi. Jessie!
- Whoo!
- Yay!
- [giggling]
- [Sarah] That was amazing.
[laughing]
[Juno] Oh! You girls were
- shitting your pants.
- [Paul] Come on. Jessie?
[Juno laughing]
That wasn't so bad. was it?
- [Beth] No. that was a piece of piss.
- [Sarah] Yeah.
[laughing]
Whoo!
[yells]
[laughing. shouting]
[giggling]
- [Paul] Bit more. Bit more.
- [Beth] Go on. Paul. fish her out.
[Paul] There. Got you.
- [Sarah] You all right?
- [Beth] Yeah.
[Juno] It's freezing. [shivers]
I can't feel my fingers.
[straining]
[Sarah] Jessie. Jessie.
Oh. come here. Oh. baby. Mmm.
Mmm.
Your cheeks are freezing.
Would you like to do that?
Come on. Jessie. it's freezing.
Let's go back to the car.
[Sarah] Go with your daddy.
- I'll just help the girls.
- [Jessie] All right.
It's okay. You go on.
We can finish up here.
You sure? Thanks. guys.
I'll see you at the hotel.
- Yeah?
- See you.
- [grunts] Thanks.
- [kisses]
Jess. when we get home.
shall I phone Rachel's mom?
See if Rachel wants to come
for dinner on Thursday?
- Yeah.
- Yeah? Okay.
When she comes around.
she can help us plan your birthday party.
- [Jessie] Okay. [giggles]
- You gonna invite any boys this time?
[Jessie giggles]
[gasps softly]
Are you okay? You seem a bit distant.
- I'm fine.
- [Jessie giggling]
[brakes squealing]
[loud crash]
[flesh squelches]
- [engine hissing]
- [liquid dripping]
[ominous music playing]
[blows air]
- [machine beeping]
- [breathing heavily]
[beeping accelerates]
- [grunts]
- [long beep]
Jess?
[ominous tone]
- [echoes] Jessie!
- [ominous tone]
[gasps]
[ominous tone]
[breathes shakily]
[panting]
- [ominous tone]
- [panting continues]
Jessie! [screams] No. Jess!
- Shh! Shh! I'm sorry.
- [sobbing]
- She's gone. I'm sorry.
- Oh. no.
[continues sobbing]
Oh. no. No. no. No. no.
[Beth] She's gone. Sarah. Shh.
- No.
- [shushing]
[Sarah continues sobbing]
[sobbing continues]
[ominous music plays]
[soft music plays]
[banjo. country music playing on radio]
- [changing radio stations]
- [Christian rock music playing]
Well. it's mud. blood and beer or sweet Jesus.
- Great. Turn that shite off.
- [radio turns off]
[sighs]
[bird chirps]
[Beth] That's frightening.
Listen. we don't have to do this. you know.
We can head back and stay in town.
[in country accent]
Get wasted. go to a barn dance.
[chuckles] Now. that is frightening.
[chuckling]
[exhales sharply]
You're right. We don't have to do this.
But I'm not gonna be the one to tell Juno.
[in normal accent]
She's a piece of work. man.
She always brings us out into the middle of--
- Well. look at it.
- [chuckles]
- She came to Scotland last year.
- Yeah. and left pretty quickly.
[soft music continues]
[engine stops]
[birds chirping. squawking]
[chuckles]
Sarah! Beth!
Juno. [chuckles] You look fantastic!
[Juno] Ah! [giggles] Right here...
- Ah. come here. Oh.
- Oh!
Let me look at you. Wow.
Everything is gonna be fine.
Better. It's gonna be great.
Becca and Sam can't wait to see you.
Why don't you go in?
- Okay.
- Give me these.
- Yeah.
- Thanks.
- Okay?
Yeah. Okay.
[Sarah] Ooh! Very nice.
How is she?
Well. she's here.
One step at a time. eh?
[Sam] Hey. hey. hey. who are you calling a fucking cheater?
[Rebecca] I'm calling you a fucking cheater.
- [laughs. gasps]
- [Sarah] Hello.
- [Sam] Hey!
- [Rebecca] Hello!
- [squeals] Oh!
- [Sarah] Hello. [chuckles]
- You do look really good.
- Thank you.
- [Sam] Oh. you look amazing.
- Sam. come here.
[Rebecca and Beth] Hey!
- [Beth] Let me put the bags down.
- [Rebecca] Oh. it's so nice to see you.
[Rebecca squeals]
- Oh. it's so nice to see you.
- [indistinct chatter]
- [Beth] I'm starving.
- Okay. go. Go. go.
- [Beth] What have you got?
- [Sam] Uh. well. there's a bit of...
Sam. Sam. Thank you so much for your letter. It meant a lot to me.
Oh. Sarah. look.
I'm so sorry that I couldn't be there.
You know. midterms and--
- It's--
- You know. Sam's gonna be Dr. Van Ney
- in. like. a year's time.
- [Sarah] No.
Please tell me it's longer than that.
- [Rebecca] I am so proud...
- Shit.
...of my little sister. [chuckles]
- Who wants a drink?
- [Rebecca] Yes!
- [Beth] Yeah!
- [Sam] Yeah. me!
- [Juno] Sarah. would you help?
- [Sarah] Yeah. yeah.
- [glasses clinking]
- [Sam] So. Beth...
[Beth] Mm-hmm?
...I hear it all starts falling apart past 25.
[Rebecca chuckles]
Is that what they teach you at medical school. yeah?
- To take the piss?
- [Sam] Uh-huh.
- Cheeky bitch.
- Ow!
- [door squeaks open]
- Can anyone make me feel any older?
Oh. here we go.
Hello. Oh. you must be the teacher.
- [Beth] Yeah. yeah.
- [Rebecca] Uh. Beth. Sarah.
this is Holly. Juno's protégé.
Really? I always thought
Juno would eat her young.
- Oh. nice.
- [chuckling]
I'm well able to handle myself. thanks very much.
[Sarah] I've heard about you.
You're that mentalist that jumps off buildings.
Ah. base jumping.
You should try it. seriously.
- Yeah.
- So you live in America now?
[blows air] Ran out of things to jump off in Galway. yeah.
- [Sarah chuckles]
- [Holly] I'm always searching
for the next big high.
- Sure you'd know all about that.
- Sorry?
Juno showed me a photo of when you used to climb together.
- Oh! [laughs]
- No.
I found this classic picture.
- [Rebecca] Ahh!
- Beth. oh. no!
- [Beth] Oh. no.
- [Sarah] Oh. no!
- [Beth] Look at the state of us.
- Oh. no!
- [Sarah] Oh. my God.
- That's bad.
- [Juno] Sexy.
- [laughter]
- "Love each day."
- [Beth] Hmm?
Just something Paul used to say.
[inhales] Anyway. Cheers.
- Here's to our adventure.
- [Sam] Oh. skoal.
- Skoal.
- Cheers.
- [wind whooshing]
- [branches rustling]
- [insects chirping]
- [owl hooting]
- [Holly] Come on. light. you bastard.
- [lighter flicking]
So. have you done Boreham Caverns before?
Oh. I saw it in a book once.
It's for tourists. It's not adventure.
[blows air] Might as well have handrails and a fucking gift shop.
- If you're a caver. jumper. climber...
- [object clatters]
...y-you just do it and not give a shite.
Or the thing that's bigger than you will get you.
[clicks]
[both chuckling]
[Juno chuckles] You want adventure. Holly?
When have I ever let you down?
What's with the--
- What?
- Nothing.
Holly. tomorrow's gonna be awesome. okay?
[Holly clicks tongue]
Take this. You'll need it.
[chuckles]
[wolf howling]
[Sarah] What about Josh. Sam?
Are you guys still together?
[Sam] Kind of. sort of. Mmm.
Different... shifts.
[door squeaks open]
Oh. my God.
- [Sarah] Oh. my Jesus!
- [all laughing]
What do you think. eh?
- Fuck.
- Don't say a fucking word. all right?
It was a Christmas present!
[all continue laughing]
[Juno snorts]
- Shut up.
- [Juno grunts]
[exhales]
What about you. Holly? Got a man?
- Oh. I'm a sports fuck like Juno.
- What?
- Rebecca too. I think.
- [all laughing loudly]
Uh. but when I'm older.
I wanna have lots of babies.
[laughing stops]
[Juno] Beth. did Sarah tell you that...
- [insects chirping]
- [indistinct chatter]
[howling in distance]
[snoring]
[shivers]
[wind whistling outside]
[snoring]
[birds screeches]
[Jessica giggling]
- [loud shattering]
- [gasps]
[groans. panting]
- [sighs]
- [bed squeaks]
[soft music playing]
[birds chirping]
[wind chimes clanging]
[panting]
- [knocking on door]
- [Rebecca groans]
Wakey... [laughs]
...wakey.
- Hmm.
- [huffs air] I feel like roadkill.
Give me five minutes.
Five minutes.
[door squeaks]
[exhales]
[handle squeaks]
[gasps. screaming]
[squeaking]
Good morning. my little ones!
- Wakey-wakey!
- [Sam groaning]
Good morning!
Is that what you call it?
It's fucking freezing.
Holly!
[door squeaks open]
[door closes]
We're leaving at 7:00. Don't be late.
Try that.
The queen is dead.
- Long live the fucking queen!
- [laughs]
- [loud thud]
- [Sam laughing]
- [bottle cap closes]
- [gulps]
- [pills rattling]
- [bottle thuds]
[Juno] Beth. you're not driving.
- If you drive. we'll never get there.
- Come on. all right.
- Paper. scissors. stone.
- What?
- Come on.
- Oh. you're a dick.
- [chuckles] Okay.
- Go on.
- There you go.
- No. wait. babe. Best of three.
- You can't...
- I'll drive.
[Holly] All right. ladies. Group photo.
[Juno] Okay. we gotta hurry though.
We're gonna be late.
- [Beth] I look like shit.
- [Holly] We all look like shit.
- Now. just give me a smile.
- [Juno] Okay.
- Hat? No hat?
- No hat. no hat. no hat.
- [camera beeping]
- All right! Run. run. run. run.
- Say "sausage"!
- [Rebecca and Sam] Sausage!
[camera shutter clicks]
[foreboding music plays]
[engine revving]
- Sarah. slow down a bit.
- I'm having fun!
She's having fun.
Oh. oh! Turn. turn. turn there.
- Let's off-road!
- Yay. let's.
- You should have some water.
- [watch beeping]
Trying to set this watch is impossible.
- The buttons are too fucking small.
- [beeping continues]
- Then leave it alone.
- Why do you wear that thing anyway?
My boyfriend gave it to me.
It's sentimental.
It's fucking mental.
Any guy that gave that to me.
I'd dump him on the spot.
[Beth] Juno. are you sure we're going the right way?
Relax. I've never been lost in my life.
- Marvelous.
- [laughs]
So. have you done these caves before?
No. but they are only level two.
They're quite safe. Don't worry.
- I wasn't.
- [Holly] Mmm.
The only danger is I might fall asleep.
Boreham Caves. More like Boredom Caves.
[birds chirping]
[both laughing]
[engine revving]
- [brakes squealing]
- [tires screech]
- [exhales] Nice parking.
- Thanks.
[keys jingling]
[car doors close]
[Holly] This one time in Galway. when-- when I free-climbed the cathedral.
and the priest chased me down the road for half a mile.
That was brilliant. [chuckles]
I shouldn't have wasted the effort. though.
- [Rebecca] Holly. shut up.
- [Holly speaks indistinctly]
- [Sam] Rebecca. leave her alone.
- [Holly mumbling]
Okay. guys. let's get moving.
We're running late.
[car door closes]
[thuds]
- [Rebecca] Come on. keep up.
- [Sam chuckles]
[Sam] Hey. Holly. wait up!
- [Rebecca] Move it. short-ass.
- [Sam laughs]
- [Beth] Oi. Carter. get to the back now.
- [Sarah] Come on. you lazy bastard.
[both laughing]
[women laughing]
[Holly] You finally caught up with me.
- [grunts]
- [Holly] Juno. are we there yet?
There's a river about half a mile ahead.
When we reach it. we follow it up to the mouth of the cave. okay?
[Sam] How does she know there's a river up ahead? I can't hear a thing.
- She can probably smell it.
- [Sam chuckles]
[Rebecca] She came up here last week to check the route out.
It's rule number one. file a flight plan and stick to it.
- And rule number two?
- [Rebecca] Don't go wandering off.
You think it's dark when you turn out the lights.
well. down there. it's pitch-black.
- You can get dehydration. disorientation.
- [Holly] Yeah. yeah. yeah.
- [Rebecca] Claustrophobia...
- [Holly] Blah. blah. blah.
...panic attacks. paranoia.
hallucinations.
visual and aural deterioration...
[Rebecca continues speaking indistinctly]
[rustles]
[loud squawking]
[flies buzzing]
[Holly] H-hey.
- [camera whirs]
- [Sam] Eurgh.
- [camera shutter clicks]
- [Beth] Yeah. lovely. Holly.
Real Kodak moment.
[Rebecca] Don't touch it.
[Beth] You wouldn't
wanna piss it off. [chuckles]
What do you think did that. Sam. a bear?
[Juno] What is this. Nature Detectives?
It could've been Bigfoot
for all you know. Come on.
[Rebecca] Sam. stop poking it with a fucking stick. Let's go.
[flies buzzing]
This is it.
You're having a laugh.
Afraid not.
[Beth] I'm an English teacher. not fucking Tomb Raider.
[Juno] You'll be fine.
- [soft thud]
- [clinking]
[Juno] Okay. Sarah. Beth. you're up next.
- Sam. stay with Becca.
- [Sam] Okay.
[Juno] Do what she does. and you'll be fine.
Holly. safety first.
I don't want any stunts this time.
- You okay?
- [Sarah] No.
See you down there.
[Rebecca] You make sure your cow's tail is locked there and there.
You hold on to this like that.
Look. you know.
I have done this before. you know.
I'm only looking after you.
And I appreciate it in small doses.
[water pattering]
[Sarah exhales]
[harness clicking]
[heavy exhale]
[Juno echoing] You gotta see this place!
It's beautiful!
You won't believe this. Beth!
[Beth echoing] Oh. shit! Shit. shit. shit.
[clicks]
- [Beth] Oh. my God. I'm gonna die.
- [Sarah exhales]
[Beth sighs]
[panting]
[sighs] Piece of piss.
Oh. my God.
[Sarah] It's incredible.
[Beth echoing] Clear!
[Holly whooping] Incoming!
- [Beth] Shit! Move!
- [rope whirs]
Holly. we do this safely. in order. following my lead. okay?
[Rebecca] Take it slow and easy.
[Rebecca grunts]
[Holly] Juno.
Smart-ass.
[foreboding music playing]
[water pattering]
- [bats screeching]
- [screaming]
- It's okay. it's okay. it's okay.
- Stop!
- They're gone. They're gone.
- [panting]
Look.
[Holly in spooky voice] One bat. Two bats.
Fifty bats. [chuckling]
- Holly. fuck off.
- [hits helmet]
Which way?
There's only one way out of this chamber. and that's down the pipe.
[clanking]
[ominous music plays]
[scraping]
[Juno] Okay.
[breathing heavily]
[harness clinking]
[gravel tinkling]
[Juno grunts softly]
[breathing heavily]
- [rumbling]
- [gasps]
- [water trickling]
- [heavy breathing]
[thuds]
[Juno] It's a drop.
[Beth grunts]
- [Juno] Okay?
- [Beth] Yeah.
[Beth] Holly. chuck us your bag.
[thuds]
[ignites. crackling]
- [Holly chuckles]
- [emergency flare ignites. crackling]
[emergency flare crackles loudly]
[Sarah] Oh. my God.
- [all laughing]
- [Rebecca] Whoa. Amazing.
[Juno laughing]
[gentle music plays]
[Jessica giggling]
[grunts softly]
[rocks clatter]
[water trickles]
[pants. blows air]
[pants. smacks lips]
[echoing thud]
- [relieved sigh]
- [Juno giggles] Find anything good?
- Jesus Christ.
- Come on. let's eat.
[Juno] Holly. would you take a break?
I just wanna take a few more shots.
This cave is a lot cooler than I thought.
Hey.
Not hungry.
You okay?
[scoffs] Juno. I won't break. I'm fine.
- I asked you for this.
- I know.
Hey. um. Sarah?
I haven't had a chance to say that I'm...
really sorry I didn't stay around longer after the accident.
Anyway...
[chuckles softly]
...we're all here for you now. okay?
Yeah.
Look. sorry. I'm feeling a bit out of it.
It's probably jet lag or something.
So I'm just gonna take a look around. okay?
Yeah. okay.
Why don't you try and find us a way through. huh?
Hey. don't go too far.
[camcorder closes]
What's up with her? She looks like she's seen a ghost or something.
She's fine.
[water pattering]
I've found the next passage!
[Beth] That's it?
It's a bit small. isn't it?
- Hey. hey. hey!
- I don't-- I don't get this.
What?
This is not how I imagined it from reading the book.
Tsk. That's why I don't trust books.
Leaves too much room for interpretation.
Something wrong?
- No.
- No. it's nothing.
[Holly] I'm taking point. guys.
- [Rebecca] Hmm. careful.
- [Juno] Careful.
Just find the way through.
We'll wait here.
[Holly] What the...
- [Holly grunts]
- [bag clatters]
[breathes deeply]
[water sloshing]
[breathes heavily]
[grunts softly]
[gravel tinkling]
- [helmet scraping]
- [grunts]
[straining]
[rumbling]
[Holly. distant] Okay. I'm through.
[grunts softly]
[grunting]
[water sloshing]
[grunts. exhales sharply]
- [grunts softly]
- [scraping]
- [child giggles]
- [Jessica's voice] Mommy.
- [exhales sharply]
- [helmet thuds]
[straining]
[exhales sharply. breathing heavily]
[water sloshing]
[grunting]
- [all laughing]
- [grunts]
[Sarah grunting]
[grunting. breathing heavily]
Sarah?
- [Sarah] Shit.
- [Beth] Are you still behind me?
Yes. [grunts]
- Shit!
- [scraping]
[straining] Shit.
Sarah!
Guys. it's Sarah.
I think she might be stuck.
[Sarah] I am stuck! [straining]
[Beth] All right. Sarah.
Calm down. Just relax.
- [gravel tinkling]
- [straining]
I can't fucking relax. Fuck. Fuck!
Okay. Sarah. you have to calm down.
And the only way you're gonna do that is to breathe. yeah?
Okay. breathe. slowly.
Just keep breathing.
[hyperventilating] I can't. I can't.
I can't-- I can't fucking breathe.
- [hyperventilating]
- [Beth] Sarah. okay. listen to me.
Just listen to my voice.
Sarah. I'm coming--
I'm coming back. Okay? Okay.
Sarah. okay? Listen to me. Keep breathing.
- Okay? Hey.
- [continues hyperventilating]
Hey. hey! [chuckles lightly]
- Okay. okay.
- [continues hyperventilating]
Okay. look here at me. Sarah. Okay?
[Sarah sobbing] Okay.
- What are you so worried about. Sarah?
- Beth...
[Beth] Look at me.
Okay. breathe. Breathe. okay?
Hey. hey. hey. listen to me. Listen to me.
- What are you afraid of?
- I can't...
- What are you so afraid of?
- ...fucking move!
You can move!
Sarah. look at me. Look at me!
[Sarah continues sobbing]
Listen. the worst thing that could've happened to you
has already happened. okay?
And you're still here.
This is just a poxy cave. and there's nothing left to be afraid of.
- I promise. Okay? Okay?
- [continues sobbing]
Hey? Hey. listen. listen. Listen to me.
You love this one.
How do you give a lemon an orgasm?
Goddamn it. let me hear you say it.
What do you do?
- You tickle its citrus. [laughing]
- [sobbing]...tickle its citrus.
[Beth] Okay. that's better.
Come on. Okay. okay.
All right. we're gonna move now.
Take hold of my arm. all right?
- [Sarah yelps]
- We're gonna move slowly.
That's it. grab my arm.
Okay. Okay. come on.
- Just slowly. Okay?
- [breathing heavily]
- Okay. come on.
- [helmet scrapes]
[both straining]
[Sarah straining] The rope bag.
- What about the rope bag?
- Okay. okay. Okay.
- [rumbling]
- [boulders crash]
Okay. fuck the rope bag. Okay. move! Now!
Now!
Hurry up!
- Now! Come on!
- [boulders crashing loudly]
Come on. Sarah! Oh. no. move! Move!
[Sarah] Fuck!
[Beth] Come on now!
[whooshing]
[muffled coughing]
[Beth] Sarah!
- [coughing]
- Sarah!
Oh! Ah!
- [Beth] Are you okay?
- [Sarah] I'm all right.
[Juno] Is everybody okay?
Is everybody okay?
- Don't fucking touch me! I'm fine.
- [Rebecca] Samantha?
[Sam] I'm here. I'm okay.
- [Rebecca] Okay. Beth. are you injured?
- [Beth] No. I'm fine.
[Juno] Nobody move till the dust has settled.
[Rebecca] Oh. don't worry. Juno.
We're not going anywhere.
[all coughing]
[Holly] You might be right about that.
[Rebecca] Jesus.
[heavy breathing]
[Holly] So. what's the story now?
[Rebecca] According to the guidebook.
this cave system has three ways in and out.
This is just one of them.
Isn't that right. Juno?
Juno. that's right. isn't it?
Check the book!
I didn't bring it.
What?
No point.
For Christ's sake. Juno.
I knew it! I knew this wasn't right!
[Beth] You filed a flight plan to mountain rescue.
If we don't report in. they'll come looking for us.
[Rebecca] Yeah. that's how it's supposed to work.
except I put in a flight plan for Boreham Caverns.
and this isn't Boreham Caverns. is it. Juno?
We're in the wrong fucking cave?
Holly was right.
Boreham Caverns was a tourist trap.
- I didn't--
- Don't try and pin
this fucking shite on me!
This is not caving. This is an ego trip.
[Juno] Come on. Rebecca.
I didn't know this was gonna happen.
This is exactly what we believe in.
We've always said. "If there's no risk. what's the point?"
Don't try and justify this.
Whe-- where are we?
It hasn't got a name. It's a new system.
I wanted us all to discover it.
- No one's ever been down here before.
- You're fucking kidding me.
Oh. God.
[Beth] How the hell are we supposed to get out?
[Holly] There may not be a way out.
[Juno] Look. there's no going back now.
We have to find a way out of this chamber and keep pushing forward.
[Beth] What the fuck do you think you're doing?
We all trusted you.
You told me this was gonna be good for Sarah.
Have you any idea what she's been through?
No. 'cause you couldn't get away fast enough. you selfish cow!
[Juno] You know what. Beth?
We all lost something in that crash.
[chittering]
Just get us out of here.
[Juno] Look. cave systems sometimes break ground.
It's a small chance.
But if we stay here. we'll die.
Let's go.
- [hammer clinking]
- [rocks clattering]
[clattering continues]
[Sam grunting]
- [Juno] Freeze!
- What?
Don't move. Sam! Just don't move!
Stay right there!
[ignites. explodes]
[crackling]
[ominous music playing]
Oh. shit. Now what?
[sighs]
[Beth panting]
- [rock thuds]
- [Rebecca] Thanks. Beth.
Now I know how far down it is.
So. what now?
One of us has to get all the way across there
so they can rig a line for you guys.
I have three cams.
I need at least three more.
Where's the other rope bag?
[Juno] Where is it?
We lost it when the cave collapsed.
- [Rebecca sighs]
- Sorry.
Right.
[Rebecca breathing heavily]
Okay. All right.
[grunting]
[breathing heavily] Okay.
[harness clinking]
[breathes heavily]
[grunts]
[grunts. exhales]
[breathing sharply. grunts]
Ah! [panting]
[Juno] Come on. Becca.
[continues panting]
[grunting in pain. breathing heavily]
[grunts in pain]
[Juno] You got it!
Come on. come on. come on. come on...
- [Juno] Come on. Rebecca.
- [breathing sharply]
Come on. Rebecca.
What are you waiting for?
- Fuck.
- [Juno] You okay?
What's wrong?
Nothing. I'm all right.
Okay.
[grunting]
Ah! [panting]
All right. more slack.
More slack. Thanks.
[yelps]
Fuck!
Ah! [panting]
- [harness clinks]
- [rope whirs]
[Rebecca grunting]
[Rebecca panting]
Okay. [gasps]
[Juno] Well done.
[Rebecca] Okay. [panting]
Throw me the red rope.
Okay.
[whirring]
- Come on.
- [Holly grunts softly]
[whirring. clinking]
[Sam grunts softly]
[Rebecca] Yeah.
Now. you make it look easy.
[sighs] Yeah. well. you make it look hard.
[whirring. clinking]
[Beth grunts] Oh...
[Juno] Don't look down. Beth.
Keep going. Just keep going.
[Rebecca] You're okay. You're safe.
Good. There you go.
[whirring. clinking]
Was this about me or you?
It's about us.
Getting back to what we used to be.
I wanted us to claim this place. name it.
I thought maybe your name.
[chuckles] Or maybe yours.
[Rebecca] You're doing well.
Come on. Come on.
There you are.
Come on. give me your hand.
[Sarah grunting]
[harness clicking]
Juno!
We'll need everything we've got.
Haul it in.
- [harness clicking]
- [rope whirs]
- [exhales]
- [rope whirring]
[kisses]
[Juno grunting]
[rope whirring]
[Juno] Fuck!
[breathing heavily]
[grunts]
[winces. grunts softly]
[grunts loudly]
[Rebecca] Reach! Reach out!
[grunts. screams]
[Sarah] Juno! No!
[yelling in pain]
[shuddering]
[gasps. whimpers]
[screams]
[grunting]
[Beth] Juno. it's okay! We've got you!
Okay. pull!
[grunting]
- [Beth] Sam!
- [Sam] Let me pass. Holly. Let me pass.
- [grunting]
- [Sam] Rebecca. show me your hand.
[panting]
- [Rebecca groaning in pain]
- [harness clicking]
[Rebecca wincing]
- [harness clicks]
- [Sam] Come on. let go. Let go.
What does it mean?
It means we're not the first.
[Beth] It's a piton. right?
Well. if there were cavers down here before.
surely there's a better chance of us getting out.
This equipment's at least a hundred years old.
No one uses stuff like this anymore.
Besides. if anyone had been down here and made it out.
they would've named it already.
- [Rebecca groans]
- [Juno] Becca. you okay?
[wincing] I'll live.
Holly. how does it look?
[Holly] It's tight again. but I can get through.
Okay. keep going.
We'll be right behind you.
- [blowing air]
- [harness clicks]
[water dripping]
[Holly] Hey. there's something down here.
[grunts]
[panting]
[water pattering]
[soft music plays]
Guys. it's amazing.
but the batteries on our lights will run out.
- So I suggest we keep moving.
- Wait a minute. Wait.
- What is it. Beth?
- Juno. light up one of your flares.
- Beth. we don't have time for this.
- Just light a flare.
[ignites. crackling]
Really lovely. Beth. but it's fucking useless.
No. look at it. What do you see?
You've got the mountain. the cave. and there's two entrances.
You are a fucking genius.
I have my moments.
This means there's another way out?
Let's find out.
Come on!
[quiet growl]
- [Holly] Bastard!
- [Sam] Which way?
[Juno] Holly. give me your lighter.
- Come on.
- Here.
Fuck!
- [Holly] Come on. come on!
- Shit.
- [whooshes]
- [lighter lid closes]
[Holly] That one!
- Hey. Holly!
- [Holly grunting]
Holly. slow down!
[Holly panting]
[Juno] Holly!
Careful!
[Holly] Daylight! I can see daylight!
[Holly continues panting]
[Juno] Holly! Care-- Slow down!
Holly. it's not daylight!
[Holly grunting]
- Help!
- [Juno] Holly!
[Juno straining]
- Help me!
- Hold on!
[Juno] He-- Guys! Hold on!
- Holly!
- [both straining]
Holly!
[gasps]
[grunts]
Sam. get down here!
Holly!
[gravel tinkling]
- Holly!
- [Holly gasps. panting]
[water sloshing]
[groaning softly]
[Juno] Holly. answer me!
[groans. grunts]
Think I hurt my leg!
[Juno] Don't move!
We're coming down to you!
[groaning] Oh. fuck.
[whimpers]
[breathing heavily]
[screams in pain]
[whimpering] No! Fuck.
[breathing heavily. growls]
Someone better get down here!
[harness clinks]
- Oh. that's fucking disgusting.
- Beth. not here. not now!
We need help. Everybody. grab a corner.
We need to move her out of the water.
Nice and easy now.
And... lift!
- [Holly screaming in pain]
- [Sam] Come on.
- [Holly] You fuckers!
- [Sam] Juno. find something
- to make me a splint out of.
- [Juno] Beth!
- [Beth] It's okay. I've got her.
- [Rebecca] Okay. Juno.
- use one of the ice axes.
- [Holly whimpers]
[Rebecca] You're gonna be all right. sweetheart.
- [Holly panting]
- [grunts]
- [Sam] Okay. okay. here we go.
- [Jessica giggling]
- [Sam] Here.
- [Holly continues panting]
Okay.
Sarah?
[Sam] Juno. I'm gonna need your help here.
- Sarah!
- Juno!
- [Juno] Okay. Give me your hand.
- [Sam] Take hold of her arm.
You're gonna have to hold her down.
What are you gonna do?
I need to dress the wound and rig up a splint.
but I can't do that while the bone is protruding.
I need to push it back in.
- Juno...
- I hate you.
I know.
Do it.
[ominous music plays]
[rustling]
[Sam] Bite down on this.
- [Rebecca] Keep hold of her.
- [Beth] Okay.
- Just fucking bite down. okay?
- [Sam] And...
- go!
- [bones crack]
[muffled screaming]
[Sam] Okay. keep her still!
- [Rebecca] Keep hold of her.
- [muffled cry]
- Come on!
- [grunts]
[muffled cries]
- [both straining]
- [bones crack]
[muffled scream]
- [Juno] Just keep biting down. baby.
- [muffled whimpering]
[overlapping talking]
- Oh!
- [bones crack]
Okay. Someone get me a medical kit.
- [spits]
- [object clinks]
Okay. okay. calm down. calm down.
It's going to be all right.
- [faint squeak]
- [gasps]
- [clicking]
- [water sloshing]
[soft clicking]
[soft clicking continues]
[soft grunt]
- [Sarah gasps]
- What are you doing?
[in shaky voice] I just saw something ahead in the tunnel.
[breathing shakily]
Sarah. I promise you.
I'm gonna get you outta here.
But I can't do it unless you're with me.
Sarah?
Sarah.
Sarah. look at me.
There's nothing there.
[Sam] That's the best I can do.
It'll hurt like hell. and you won't be able to put any weight on it.
but at least you can move.
[Juno] They combed these mountains centuries ago.
Anyone trapped down here would be a skeleton by now.
- That is just what it looked like. Beth.
- What what looked like?
- Sarah thinks she saw someone back there.
- Saw what?
I don't think I saw someone.
I saw someone.
No. you heard something. and you saw what you wanted to see.
It's the dark. It plays tricks on people.
I can describe to you exactly what I saw.
What did you see?
A man. I saw a man.
- [Rebecca] Now. are you sure?
- Yes. And it's not the first time.
I thought I saw someone before. but now. I'm sure.
Look. if there is somebody down here. then maybe they can help get us out.
Sarah. there's no one down here.
Forget about it.
Hey. hey. We have to get Holly out of here.
Okay? This is all that matters right now.
- Beth!
- Sam. what do we do?
It's okay.
It isn't-- Fuck. [sighs]
Fuck me. [sobs softly]
[Juno] You've gotta keep warm.
[Beth] Why are we walking away?
There was daylight back there.
[Juno] It wasn't daylight.
It was phosphorus in the rock.
We're two miles underground.
The only light down here is ours.
- [thud]
- [Holly groans loudly]
[Holly] Well. it looked like fucking daylight to me.
[Holly grunting in pain]
[breathing heavily]
[whooshing]
Right tunnel!
[water dripping]
[Holly groaning]
- [Sam] I got you. Okay?
- [Holly grunting in pain]
[water bubbling. pattering]
[Juno grunting softly]
[Juno gasps softly]
[both grunting]
[Holly groaning in pain]
Ah! [pants]
[grunts. groans in pain]
[Beth] Jesus. What is this place?
[Sarah] Holly. where's the infrared button?
[beeps]
Dead animals. Hundreds of them.
[Beth] This is not good. guys.
- [Sam] Can we get out of here?
- Which way?
Come on.
- I don't know.
- [Beth] What do you mean you don't know?
There's no breeze. It could be any one of these tunnels. Take your pick.
[Rebecca yelling hysterically]
Oh. fuck it.
[yells] Hello?
- Please!
- [yelling] Is there anybody there?
[Beth yells] Hello?
- [all screaming]
- [creature growling]
[Juno] What was that?
- [Beth] It's there! It's up there!
- [Juno] There! There!
[Beth] There on the roof!
[Juno] What was that?
- What was that?
- What the hell was that? Jesus!
- [Sam] Okay. okay.
- [whimpering. panting]
[Sarah] Fuck it. no! Did you see?
What was that?
What the fuck was that?
[Rebecca] I don't know. It moved so fast.
I could barely see it!
I've never seen anyone climb like that before.
- I told you I saw someone!
- That was not a human being!
Screw this! Let's take our chances and pick a tunnel. Move!
[creature screeching]
[Juno whimpers]
- [soft growling]
- [Sam] What's happening?
- [Beth] Oh. shit. It's circling us.
- [clicking]
[whooshing]
- [Beth] Where is it?
- [rattling]
[Sarah] This way! Move!
- [Juno] Holly! Let's go!
- [Beth] We've gotta move!
- Come on. come on!
- Move it!
[Juno] Come on. Holly. move it! Let's go!
- Juno. the flare. get rid of it!
- [Sam] Come on. Rebecca!
Fuck. [mumbles]
- Holly. keep moving! Come on!
- [Holly grunts]
[screeches]
- [all screaming]
- [thud]
[grunts. screams in pain]
- [screeching]
- [Holly gasps]
- [Holly screaming]
- [flesh squelching]
- [hissing]
- Holly!
- [screeches]
[Rebecca] Sam. run!
Holly!
[screeching]
- [hissing]
- Let her go!
- Oh. my God! Holly!
- [shrieking]
[panting]
Sarah! [grunts]
Sarah. run!
[Sarah gasps loudly]
- [headlamp shatters]
- [body thuds]
[Juno shrieking]
Get off! Get off! Get off!
[screeching]
[grunting loudly]
[low growling]
Get away. you fucker!
- [grunts loudly]
- [creature whimpering]
Holly! [sobbing]
[low growling]
- [screeches]
- [shouts]
[screams]
[creature growling]
- [Juno screams]
- [growling]
- [Juno shrieking]
- [continues growling]
- [creature screeching in pain]
- [Juno screaming]
- [Juno yells]
- [thud]
[Juno panting]
[grunting loudly]
- [clatters]
- [Juno shouts]
[shuddering]
- [gulps]
- [flesh squelches]
[Beth grunts]
[grunts]
[somber music playing]
- [labored breathing]
- [Juno gasps]
[Beth grunting]
[creature screeching]
[Beth. softly] Don't leave me.
[grunting]
[creature screeching]
[sobbing softly]
[breathing shakily]
Oh. fuck. My battery's gone dead.
[Sam] Where are they?
[breathing shakily]
What's happened to the others? [sobbing]
Becca. Becca. please say we're gonna get out of here.
- [whispering] Shh. Okay. Okay. Okay.
- [Sam sobbing] Okay.
[Rebecca] Okay.
All right. Go. Go.
[Sam continues sobbing]
[Jessica's voice whispering] Mommy.
Mommy.
Mommy. if you're really ready--
[screeches]
[sniffs]
[retches]
[retches. coughs]
[groans]
[ominous music plays]
- [creature growls]
- [gasps]
[shuddering]
- [loud thud]
- [gasps. whimpers]
[creature screeching]
[Sarah whimpering]
[footsteps]
[creatures howling]
[creatures munching]
- [whooping]
- [flesh squelching]
- [creature screeching]
- Oh. fuck. Fuck.
[panting]
[creature screeches]
[Sam whispers] Fuck.
[Rebecca whispers] Turn the light off.
Quiet.
- [grunting]
- [munching]
[munching]
[gags]
[growls. snarls]
[screeching]
[Juno] Sarah!
- [echoing] Sarah!
- [screeches]
[running footsteps receding]
Okay.
[breathing shakily] Okay.
[snarling]
[growling]
[screeching]
[snarling]
[tense music playing]
[Rebecca mouthing]
It can't see us.
[watch alarm beeping]
- [beeping continues]
- [growls]
[beeping continues]
- [beeping continues]
- [snarling]
- [beeping stops]
[beeping resumes]
- [distant beeping]
- [softly] Becca?
Sam? Becca? Sam?
[yells] Becca?
- Sam!
- [beeping stops]
- Becca!
- It's Juno.
- [Juno] Becca!
- [Rebecca] The noise she's making.
she'll bring every one of those things down on her head.
- As long as it's not on mine.
- [Juno yells] Sam!
[gasps]
Becca?
[Juno in distance] Becca!
[echoes] Sam!
[Sarah sobbing softly]
[breathing heavily]
Huh?
[liquid sloshing]
[object clatters]
[gasps]
Oh. God.
[Juno in distance] Sam!
Becca!
[yells] Anyone?
Sam!
[growls]
[Sarah sobs softly] Sorry. I'm sorry.
[grunts] I'm sorry.
[gasps softly] I'm sorry.
[clattering]
[liquid splashing]
[object clatters]
[object clinking]
[grunting]
Fuck. Okay.
Okay.
[grunts]
Okay. It's all clear.
- [rustling]
- [gasps]
[exhales] Okay.
- [screeching]
- [Rebecca screams]
Sam. run!
[panting. gasps]
[Rebecca grunting]
[growling]
- [snarling]
- [Rebecca whimpering]
[screeching in pain]
- [Juno grunts]
- [bones snap]
[spits]
[panting]
[Rebecca] Oh. we heard you crying for Sarah.
Where are the others?
[Juno sobs]
They-they took Holly.
Beth...
Beth's dead.
[kicks creature. grunts]
[sniffles]
[Juno sobbing]
Sam...
what is that thing?
I don't know.
Well. it does look human.
Come on. We need to find the way out before those things find us.
No.
Sam. tell us what we're fighting.
Well...
they're totally blind.
And judging from what we've seen.
I'd say they use sound to hunt with. like a bat.
And they've evolved perfectly to live down here in the dark.
Whatever they are. they go to the surface to hunt.
and they bring their food back down here to eat through an entrance.
Listen. if we can stay quiet enough and evade these fuckers...
I think I found the way out.
You think?
The climbing gear we found.
Whoever brought that down here marked their route.
I found those markings.
What are we waiting for?
Sarah.
I'm not leaving without Sarah.
[clangs]
[Beth gasps] Sarah?
[Sarah] Oh. God. [whimpering]
Oh. my God. [strains]
- Oh. God. no.
- [gasps]
Sarah... run.
- [labored breathing]
- I'm getting you out of here.
[Beth groaning] Oh. don't!
Don't touch me. Don't touch me.
[labored breathing]
I heard Juno calling me.
I'm gonna go and find her.
and we're gonna come back and we're gonna get you out.
No. Stay away from her.
- What?
- She did this to me.
What?
- She left me.
- No. she didn't. No.
- Shh.
- Sarah.
[Beth grunting]
Don't trust her.
[labored breathing]
You find your own way out.
It's okay. It's all right.
I'm not gonna leave you. Beth.
I'm not gonna leave you.
I'm not leaving you here. okay?
Come here. [strains] Beth!
[labored breathing]
[choking]
It's Juno's.
It's from Paul.
No.
[labored breathing. grunting]
[Sarah sobbing]
Sorry.
Please...
[distant growling]
[sobbing indistinctly] Oh. that's-- Fuck.
Please come...
Please. [continues sobbing]
Sarah.
Don't leave me like this. Please.
- Oh. please don't ask me to do that.
- Please.
Beth. I can't do that. I can't do that.
Please.
Please. [grunts]
[creature screeches]
Okay. Shh. Close your eyes.
[Sarah sobs]
- [Sarah grunts]
- [thud]
[flesh squelching]
[panting]
- [screeching]
- [Sarah screams]
[thud]
[growling]
[screeching]
- [grunting. kicking]
- [flesh squelching]
[trilling]
[groaning]
[growls. screeches]
[suspenseful music playing]
[bubbling]
[exhales]
[screeching]
[Sarah screaming]
[thud]
[screeching]
[Sarah panting]
[screeching continues]
- [flesh squelches]
- [screeching stops]
[Sarah panting]
[grunts]
[creature growls]
[snarling]
[rattling]
[soft growling]
[screeches]
[thud]
[grunts. exhales]
[yells]
- [distant screeching]
- [Rebecca gasps]
[Juno] Hurry. Move!
[panting]
Sarah.
S-Sarah!
Look. she's dead. Juno.
We can't wait for her.
Come on!
[Juno] Sarah! This way. Sarah!
Sarah!
[Rebecca] Sam. come back!
[soft growling]
[whispers] Sarah?
Sarah.
[rattling]
- Run!
- [screeching]
[panting]
Ow!
[water splashes]
Oh. fuck! [grunts]
[grunts]
[straining]
[Juno] Fuck.
- Come on!
- [Rebecca] Just stop her!
I'll be right behind you!
[grunts]
[Juno] Sam!
What are you doing?
Come back!
Becca!
You haven't got enough rope!
Sam! Turn around!
[panting]
- What are you doing? Turn around!
- Sam. baby! Sam. baby!
- [breathing shakily]
- [Juno] Sam.
[Rebecca] Sam.
Sam. turn around. You can come back.
Please. baby. listen to me. Please!
- [screeching]
- [gasps]
[Rebecca] No!
- Sam!
- [rattling]
- [Rebecca] No!
- [screeching]
- What are you doing?
[action music plays]
[screeching]
[flesh squelches]
Sam!
[yells] Sam!
[creature screeching in pain]
[Rebecca] No!
- [screaming hysterically]
- [water splashes]
[wailing]
- [screeching]
- [screams] Juno!
- No! [screaming]
- [Juno] No! No!
- [screaming]
- Becca!
- [growling]
- [screaming]
[Juno inhales deeply]
[water splashes]
[muffled growl]
[growling in pain]
[gasping for air. coughs]
[breathing shakily]
- [grunts]
- [thud]
[ominous music plays]
[grunts]
[breathes sharply. grunts softly]
[yells]
[Juno grunts. gasps]
[Sarah breathing sharply]
What happened to you?
[breathes shakily]
Rebecca?
[softly] No.
What about Beth?
[sobs softly]
[softly] Sarah. she didn't make it.
You saw her die?
[sobs softly] Uh...
Come on.
[ignites. crackling]
[water pattering]
[rattling]
Come on. Come on.
[screeches]
[hisses. growls]
- [growls]
- [Juno grunts]
[creatures screeching]
[Juno screams]
- [Juno yelps]
- [screeches]
[screeches in pain]
[Sarah yelps]
- [thudding]
- [screeches in pain]
- [flesh squelching]
- [screeching in pain]
[thudding]
[screeching in pain]
- [grunting]
- [thudding]
- [flare crackling]
- [screeching]
- [yells]
- [screeching stops]
[squelching]
[spits]
[ominous music plays]
[panting]
[distant screeching]
[screeching]
[Juno screams in pain]
[grunts]
[sobbing softly]
[creature screeches]
[grunts]
- [grunts]
- [screeching]
[Juno screaming]
[gasps]
[panting. grunting]
[gasps. grunting]
[dramatic music playing]
[gasps softly]
[dramatic music sting]
[rustles]
[gasps]
[exhales deeply]
[yelling hysterically]
[yelping]
[sobbing] Oh. God! Oh. God!
- [panting]
- [keys jingling]
[engine starts]
[engine revving]
[triumphant music playing]
[wailing]
[wipers squeaking]
[continues wailing]
[horn blaring]
[window whirring]
[breathing heavily]
[ominous music sting]
[screaming]
[creature screeches]
[creature screeching]
[rattling]
[Jessica's voice] Mommy.
[dramatic music playing]
[creatures screeching]
[loud screech]
[soft music plays]
[clicking]
[music fades out]